<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-04-04T02:07:17+05:30</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">alternative hypothesis</title><subtitle>Insights in the intersection of Finance, Business, Technology, and Self-Mastery.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Morality of investing and the grey area that’s not very talked about.</title><link href="/blog/2020/morality-in-investing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Morality of investing and the grey area that's not very talked about." /><published>2020-08-31T18:30:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-08-31T18:30:00+05:30</updated><id>/blog/2020/morality-in-investing</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/morality-in-investing/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid rounded z-depth-1&quot; src=&quot;/assets/img/7_yaminisood.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I agree with this. If you look at morality in the process of investing, and dig deeper into every company, I am sure you can find enough dirt on people, management and their products. When you do that, you won’t be able to invest in any company as a moral person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep aside your morality and stop being a hypocrite. You are into investing for only one thing - money. You’re not doing the society a service by investing into companies. Your primary motive is profit. Acknowledge that to yourself first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I draw a line too. I won’t do anything unethical and won’t invest in companies that breach ethics of running a company. But beyond that, speaking morals and investing in only “feel good” companies is a bunch of hogwash. If you only invested that way, you wouldn’t make money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are these “good” companies that make environment-friendly products, customer health friendly products. If you dig deeper into their corporate culture, their management, and people, you can find some rot somewhere that will put you off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Draw a line and stop fooling yourself saying by not investing in a cigarette company, you’re not contributing to millions of deaths. By visiting a tea-stall regularly and buying tea, you’re prospering the tea-wala’s business where he sells cigarettes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you get enough data points, each and every one of us is contributing to millions of deaths - animals, plants, humans too. Our fridge, AC, etc., cause harm to the environment. We use vehicles, cars, buses, which cause pollution. If you drive stupidly, it causes accidents. If you’re a non-vegetarian, you’re basically contributing to the deaths of millions of plants. You are indirectly responsible for the loss of gallons of water, and deaths of lots of animals. Where are your morals here? Prospering that chai-wala by giving him business, you’re contributing to cigarette smokers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because, if nobody went there to drink tea, how can he have a stall, how can he sell cigarettes? Significant percentage of the cigarette sales in India happen in such chai-shops. Aren’t you contributing to deaths then? If you look deep enough, you’ll be guilty of a lot of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, call a spade a spade and chill the heck out. Your primary intention is to make money. Try and do it ethically without cheating anyone if you can. And, draw your line where that ends. If you still want to look at morals, as suggested, leave stock markets, live in a farm land, and run a charity.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I made 400% profit in a year with Discretionary Trading. Here’s how I did it!</title><link href="/blog/2020/made-400-percent-profits/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I made 400% profit in a year with Discretionary Trading. Here's how I did it!" /><published>2020-08-05T23:30:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-08-05T23:30:00+05:30</updated><id>/blog/2020/made-400-percent-profits</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/made-400-percent-profits/">&lt;p&gt;This is my Zerodha P&amp;amp;L report. I trade a certain portion of my capital with Zerodha and this has been my performance so far. I do discretionary trading on Zerodha, systematic trading on Interactive Brokers. Part of the reason for all this profit is knowing when to take the trade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid rounded z-depth-1&quot; src=&quot;/assets/img/4.400returns.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This performance has been on a capital of 24L. I know that it’s over and above 400%, which is due to the intraday leverage provided by Zerodha that I used. At first, I was doing NIFTY options, but then moved to NIFTY Futures and Stock Futures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know it’s awesome and everything. Many people in my close circle have been asking me to teach how I did this. So, I am planning to conduct a workshop as well. I am expecting 2500 people to sign up for the initial webinar. I ll be charging 2500 rupees per person for the webinar and I ll be donating 50% to charity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those who attend my webinar will also qualify for a discounted rate for my actual workshop. I will be conducting the workshop in different cities across India. Mumbai, Delhi, Jaipur, Bangalore, Hyderabad, Chennai and Goa are under consideration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am going to teach you all that I know. People with capital upwards of 5L can attend the webinar, and thereafter the workshop. There will only be 50 seats per workshop location and each seat will cost 50K incl gst.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will teach you my successful discretionary trading strategy. Using this strategy my win rate is over and above 75%. I will support all the webinar and workshop attendees for 6 months. If you perform well, I might even invest capital with you. You would have to win zerodha 60day challenge for qualifying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus tip: I’ll give you a licensed backtesting software for free too. I will walk you through my method of identifying price action setups. I will also teach you how to backtest simple ideas and start trading small. I will also teach you how to compound your capital aggressively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have read thus far, I am sorry to say that you are so naive that you almost believed this. Well, up until this point I was just kidding. That was an elaborate HTML5 inspect elements + photoshop work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This particular PNL screenshot took me about half hour to make. I know there might be one or two flaws here and there. But, to someone scrolling by, it looks absolutely perfect, flawless - can’t doubt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can do this with every picture and make it look legitimate and believable. If I can, so can anyone else. And, NOTE: I am not even a pro at photoshop. I am at an intermediate level with photoshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just ask yourself how much more greedy you can get. Your greed will set in motion the path to ruin. Have some common sense and stop believing in screenshots.  If you decide to attend anyone’s seminar or workshop, be extra careful. Most of these workshops cost as much as your monthly salary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A proper trainer must be a trader first and foremost. And, he/she must have verifiable track record. Or atleast have a public track record of skin in the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take @bhatiamanu for example. He has his systems in place. He won’t share his strategies. But he posts his trades. He’s accounted for each trade, and has shown in public what the win ratio for his system is. That’s skin in the game. (I am not endorsing him, this is only an example).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trainer must share broker verified statements, or actual trades with proper verifiability. He/she should do this on a public platform. This helps you understand his/her track record. These are some of the things you can use to assess whether a trainer is legitimate and if he/she is going to help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People like @madan_kumar do this in their workshops, showing their track record. They also publicly share their trades with verifiable tracking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s just the first level. Even if a trader is successful at such trades, and has an amazing track record, it doesn’t mean he is a great teacher. It’s always going to be a gamble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If they are great teachers also, your psychology and the methods they teach may not match. Avoid workshops where you need to pay to learn options basics or derivatives. If you Google, you can find the best content on derivatives and option strategies for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond all this, if someone has a well structured course/program/workshop - you will know. This will become evident through the feedback their past participants provide. Dig up the trainer’s old tweets about workshops. You can see the comments from the past participants. Go ahead and contact them, ask their opinion, and then take a step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To sum up: Wanting to grow and improve as a trader is all good and fine. But don’t get lured into the world of trading by looking at flashy profit numbers. Don’t think you can get there attending couple of seminars and workshops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trading is hard work. You don’t realise what kind of hard work it is to succeed in it. When you actually get there, it may not be the life you thought you wanted to have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think trading is exciting and thrilling, and if you’re getting in for that - you’re a gambler. Your gambling instincts are kicking in and it’s fine.  Just recognize that and stop yourself before you risk ruin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trading - the actual process is the most boring job in the world. Discretionary trading after a particular stage is emotionally exhausting. Only 1% of all successful traders continue in the discretionary way even after age 35.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop buying dreams from those who are selling dreams. Be realistic. Yes, you can make 400-500% initially with a small capital in a year itself. But before you get there, you’d get wiped out atleast once, most people blow up 2,3,4,5 times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take all FinTwit with a heavy tablespoon of salt and put in all the work you can. Do your work before you approach anyone else for mentoring. If you don’t put in the work and expect someone else to handhold you through, you’re not meant for this field. Period.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This is my Zerodha P&amp;amp;L report. I trade a certain portion of my capital with Zerodha and this has been my performance so far. I do discretionary trading on Zerodha, systematic trading on Interactive Brokers. Part of the reason for all this profit is knowing when to take the trade.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Systematic Way To Approach Discretionary Trading</title><link href="/blog/2020/systematic-approach-to-discretionary-trading/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Systematic Way To Approach Discretionary Trading" /><published>2020-08-02T23:30:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-08-02T23:30:00+05:30</updated><id>/blog/2020/systematic-approach-to-discretionary-trading</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/systematic-approach-to-discretionary-trading/">&lt;p&gt;As a beginner in the stock market, you’d do way better by avoiding intraday trading altogether. Instead, you must focus on positional trades using a higher time frame analysis. This way, you make fewer decisions. These decisions have a longer time to play out. You also pay fewer commissions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of getting rich in stock market is by avoiding dumb decisions. Dumbasses coming into the stock market hoping to make their yearly salary in a month or a week go bust. Coz these are dumb people who blow away money like fireworks. Poof and gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, as a beginner, don’t touch FNO without knowing what you’re doing. If you are keen on exploring FNO, educate yourself. Explore the ins and outs of the mechanisms of the fno market and then get in - with only one lot. Experiment with one lot first and then scale as you grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Play only with cash and carry (CNC), analyse stocks using charts, and play longer time frame. Even if it is 100-200 rupees, see how you play it out. See if you can identify setups and buy 1 or 2 shares of that stock and see how far it goes. Rinse and repeat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a stock is 300-400 rupees, and you’re seeing a particular setup in that stock, buy 1 share. Doesn’t hurt. Delivery is free. You’d pay STT/taxes, but they’ll be negligible. What you have to do is first observe and skinny dip. Once you see consistency, you can scale up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strive to make an average of 5 points in every trade you put on, in a consistent manner. At 1 share a trade, it’s not much. As you get consistent and go to 100 shares, you make 500 rupees per trade on average. When you go to futures, it’s at least 1000-2000 units per lot, and you make 10000 rupees on average.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how you approach discretionary trading. You don’t get enticed by the idea of making 45 lakhs in 6 days. You don’t approach the market shooting in the blind. You don’t start with option selling or anything exotic. You only see 45 lakhs in 6 days as the headline. A rational person would ask - “under what capital?” It could be 25 crores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you make 45 lakhs in 6 days out of 25 crores, that’s like 2% return. Very ambitious, high risk, but definitely possible. But you come in with 1-2L capital and hope to make 45L in 6 days, you’re setting yourself up to part with all your capital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You must not look at absolutes, but at % terms. As you grow, that’s what will matter much more than absolute terms. Even as an educated person, 45 lakhs in 6 days may sound alluring. But think about what kind of work has gone into it over the years to to get to that place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any legitimate investor/trader who makes 45 lakhs over 6 days has years of market experience. They spent years developing good intuition. They developed instincts to know where to place the trade and where to exit. Do not attempt to emulate that from get go. If you do that, you will fail. And you will fail hard. You’ll be messaging one of those MTM traders telling them you have lost 30L/50L/80L so far. You’ll be asking them how to recover it, asking them to teach you to trade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Al Brooks says, first focus on making 5 points per trade in 1 share. Then 10 shares. Then 100 shares. Then 1 lot. Then 10 lots. Then 100 lots. You need nothing else. Pick up one instrument, study it daily, master the way you find setups, wait for setups and play. Build consistency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you do all this and once you have a certain level of success, then you can look into diversifying. All this hoopla going around workshops and seminars is useless if you can’t trade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make use of whatever books/videos available online. Take REAL trades on your broker platform. Start with higher time frame though. Start with only 1 share of any nifty50 shares, preferably ones within 100-500 rupee range. Keep your risk capital less, risk lesser, and learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Observe, learn for one year, and build consistency. And then slowly scale up. If you do this, over 5 years, there’s no way but up and about consistently making money.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">As a beginner in the stock market, you’d do way better by avoiding intraday trading altogether. Instead, you must focus on positional trades using a higher time frame analysis. This way, you make fewer decisions. These decisions have a longer time to play out. You also pay fewer commissions.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The only 3 books you need to master trading options and futures.</title><link href="/blog/2020/3-books-for-derivatives/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The only 3 books you need to master trading options and futures." /><published>2020-07-31T22:30:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-31T22:30:00+05:30</updated><id>/blog/2020/3-books-for-derivatives</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/3-books-for-derivatives/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To learn about derivatives trading, read and internalize the following books.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Options Futures and other Derivatives - John Hull&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Option Volatility and Pricing - Sheldon Natenberg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Options as a strategic investment - Lawrence Macmillan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There you go. I saved you at least one lakh rupees in seminar/workshops that teach you options basics. I also saved you another lakh on workshops to learn about option strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you thought you can learn and master options and futures within a day or two, you couldn’t be more wrong. That said, if you have the patience to go over these books and take time to understand, it will serve you well. This way, you’d do much better than if you were to go through a workshop costing 50,000 rupees to 5 Lakhs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save your money. Spend 1000-2000 on these books if need be (you can easily find them online for free) and put in the work. No two ways about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NOTE: Natenberg’s book and Hull’s book are the most recommended books. These books are a regular feature on recommended readings at buy and sell side firms. Hedge funds, market making firms, proprietary trading firms, you name it.  Goldman, JPM, Credit Suisse, Citadel, etc., mandate going through these books during training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, watch and observe the FNO securities in the market every day. Strengthen your basics alongside to develop mastery over the theoretical framework. If you do this, you won’t need to do anything else for your journey trading derivatives. You only need to apply your knowledge in practice.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">To learn about derivatives trading, read and internalize the following books.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Work with people you want to become like.</title><link href="/blog/2020/paulgraham-work-people/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Work with people you want to become like." /><published>2020-07-30T23:30:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-30T23:30:00+05:30</updated><id>/blog/2020/paulgraham-work-people</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/paulgraham-work-people/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid rounded z-depth-1&quot; src=&quot;/assets/img/6_paulgraham.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No truer truth than this. Back at my first job, regular interactions with people and lack of self introspection led me to become almost like the people around me. Gossipping, enjoying breakout room banter, playing foosball to take the steam off, thinking about cars, etc., became the norm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one point, I even considered applying for a housing loan, when I was merely 23. That would have blocked most of my earnings away. Also, I wouldn’t have been able to experiment with the things I have experimented with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many in my team and adjacent teams were buying cars, with the help of a loan. Influenced by them, I was dreaming of buying an Innova/Tavera. This was to make passive income, attaching the car to a travel operator like SRS. I was also desiring a Honda Jazz for personal use. I’d be lying if I said I wasn’t crushing on a BMW X5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was gorging on sweets and chocolates that people brought from the US. That’s what people around me did, and I was just fitting in. No self control. Eating like there’s no tomorrow. There are certain things I didn’t do. But there was definitely heavy influence of the level of vibration in thoughts around me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only after I left the job, it became evident as to what extent I had gotten socially conditioned (because of the group I had been with). Starting my business and spending some time alone for a year also helped. I stopped liking so many things. I stopped thinking about things in the ways I thought about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier when I was working, I used to look at the cars on the road in awe. S-Cross, Jazz, Innova Crysta, Honda Accord, Audi A5, BMW X5, BMW C series, Porsche Cayenne, etc., were some cars I drooled over. This was mostly due to the influence of avid car researchers and buyers around me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever I saw one of these cars on the street, I used to imagine how it would be if I could have one of those for myself. I almost wanted to finalise on the Honda Jazz with the signature maroon color of Honda city. I also almost decided on getting a home in Coimbatore on loan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both times, the little common sense I had left prevailed, due to my intuition screaming at me “Man! don’t screw yourself because you can’t think for yourself. Stop being a dumbass and stop following other dumbasses around.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am talking about people who have mostly settled for whatever they got in life. They don’t want to put any additional effort in life. Saturdays and Sundays are holidays for them. They have never touched a book after their college. They talk about cinema, cricket, politics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the people who stay for longer hours in the office to get visibility. They think longer hours equate to other people thinking they are working so hard. They buy everything on credit. They have a bunch of credit cards lying around. They buy cars, premium bikes, house, land, everything on loan. Every month, before they receive their salaries, their debtors will receive money from their account. They get to keep like 1/5th of what they earn. They save a little. They spend it on trips and gadgets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only after 30, after they have kids, they start thinking about financial planning. Sometimes, they end up going to the wrong financial planner and shell out so much for nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you work with these kinds of people, when you spend 10-12 hours a day with such a group, you can’t help but become them. From the Director, the Manager, to your peers and juniors, everyone in one direction, you can only exert so much will power to swim against the current.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, don’t waste your will power spending time and life at such a place around people who haven’t grown since their early 20s. Don’t be around people who have stagnated personally. These are all wormholes that will suck you in and never let you out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One year out of that company and into my business, (most of which I spent alone), had some impact. That time helped me reflect on the misalignment between my spirit and what I have gotten conditioned to believe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One year later, cars no longer excited me. BMW X5 still remains my dream car. But I don’t go gaga over any car. I don’t even look at cars. There was a time I used to go page to page on TeamBHP spending hours researching cars. I knew the specification of almost every car in market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me a while to realise “what’s the point?”. A car is to get you from A to B safely. Any regular car would do and when we decide to get a car, we’ll think about it. Same thing with home. I have an image of a dream home. But it’s not a priority to get it on loan for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of debate on whether home loan is good or bad. At least early in your career, don’t take on debt. And when you take on debt, make sure you have an equal amount of cash invested in assets that pay you more than the interest you pay the bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, let’s say you get a loan for 1 crore at 15% interest. Also, you have 1 crore cash invested in assets making you 20% per annum. You pay 15% of it to the bank, and keep the remaining 5% reinvested. That’s what a smart person would do, at least early on for personal purchases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To sum up, the quality of people you work with is more important than the quality of your friends. Once you’re well into your proper family life, you spend more time with your colleagues than with your family or friends. So, make sure you work with those you look up to, and not those whom you consider a bunch of morons. Work with people smarter than you, more intelligent, more hard working, more efficient, and more productive. To get to choose who you work with, raise your standards first.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A word of warning about Tradetron’s strategy subscription services.</title><link href="/blog/2020/warning-tradetron/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A word of warning about Tradetron's strategy subscription services." /><published>2020-07-30T19:30:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-30T19:30:00+05:30</updated><id>/blog/2020/warning-tradetron</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/warning-tradetron/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;guys-a-word-on-tradetron1-or-any-backtest--algo-trading-service-out-there&quot;&gt;Guys, a word on @Tradetron1 or any backtest + algo trading service out there.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://tradetron.tech/strategy/102&quot;&gt;Options SAR strategy&lt;/a&gt; first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some problems I see in this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Look at this strategy. I don’t know what this strategy is, but right out of the bat, it shows the max DD as ~23% in one place, and about 77%.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid rounded z-depth-1&quot; src=&quot;/assets/img/5_tradetron_1.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid rounded z-depth-1&quot; src=&quot;/assets/img/5_tradetron_2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When you look at the PNL figures in the page, on a monthly breakup, you don’t know the actual PNL. Their figures haven’t taken into account the spread, slippage, and commissions.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Annual return of 1455.3% and max drawdown of 23.4% might look outstanding. But it also looks unrealistic. Like, heavily unrealistic.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;One year of backtest may look wonderful. But, for you to know that a strategy has longevity and will stand the test of time, it needs at least 7-10 years of backtest. Or, if there are 1000 trades, the backtest report would be significant enough to proceed to the next step.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The total number of trades, points per trade - these two parameters are very important. If the strategy made 1400% on a year’s worth of trades that are over and above 500 trades, let’s do some math. 1400% of 30k is 420k. 420k in nifty points is 5600.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Let’s assume the total trades per year to be 500 for illustration.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Let’s keep 1 point as commission, 1 point slippage on either side, 1 point bid-ask spread on either side. That makes it 5 points.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;5*500 = 2500 points. Deduct 2500 points from the total 5600 points. This cuts the returns by 45%
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you have 2100 points net, and 500 trades a year, how many points do you make per trade? 4.2 points give or take a few basis points. Not too good.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you backtest this over last 10 years, I am damn sure that some years will go deep underwater. You just don’t know how much underwater it would go, if this strategy would wipe you out. If it historically wiped you out, it will most likely wipe you out this time too.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And so, the following things are important to see in a backtest report at least as a first pass filter.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;At least 10 years of backtest.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;No of trades&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Max drawdown&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Time drawdown&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Time from max dd to new equity high&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;CAGR/maxDD at least &amp;gt; 1.5&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;decent unlevered CAGR.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;at least 7-10 points per trade if NIFTY&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;at least 20-30 points per trade if BANKNIFTY&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s important these backtests weren’t run on SPOT, but run on Futures. Option prices move based on Futures. So, unless the backtests ran on actual options data, backtests run on Futures should be your next best bet. If you backtest a strategy on NIFTY and it gives 3000 points per year, the same on futures would give ~1700-2000 pts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my backtesting, this has been the approximate case. Account for 30-40% reduction in no of points backtesting in futures. That would be the case if you trade live too. When that happens, another 5 points per trade in commissions and slippage will happen. That would render these systems useless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lot of things that goes on in the background for backtesting. Unless you know the strategy and you have manually backtested it for at least 7-10 years, don’t trade it. Don’t sign up for online auto-trade platforms unless they provide comprehensive reports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be especially wary of platforms that show mere 6 months backtest and ask you to trade it. I think Tradetron is a good initiative and effort. That said, just don’t jump in looking at these shiny equity charts and numbers, and commit money to trading these strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;End of day, you’re going to conclude that most of these services are useless. They only separate you from your money. You’ll go only back to putting money in shitty mutual funds that give sub-par returns. So, just don’t experiment with money unless you know what you’re doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Tradetron or any similar service for that matter, first let the service exist for 2-3 years. At the end of 3 years, see their track record and then decide. Don’t jump in as beta test users. This is not some SaaS software to jump and test for brownie points. This is real money in line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, don’t backtest any option strategy for only one or two years and jump into trading. If you do that, you’ll find out the hard way that you made a mistake. Stop allowing greed to blind you and let some common sense seep in.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">From Zero to Live in Trading - Introduction</title><link href="/blog/2020/zero-to-live-introduction/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="From Zero to Live in Trading - Introduction" /><published>2020-07-25T22:10:16+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-25T22:10:16+05:30</updated><id>/blog/2020/zero-to-live-introduction</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2020/zero-to-live-introduction/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;introduction-to-systematic-trading&quot;&gt;Introduction to Systematic Trading&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Systematic Trading is trading with well defined rules without any space for discretion.  The two broad types of strategies relevant to retail traders are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trend-Following&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mean-Reversion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are other types of strategies such as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arbitrage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Market Making&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Liquidity Rebate Trading&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Predatory Trading&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Behavioral Trading&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Event Trading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These strategies are beyond the scope of what retail traders could execute. Infrastructure or commissions limit retailers from getting into these strategies.The Frequency of trading strategies also plays an important role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three major types of trading based on frequency:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Low Frequency&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;High Frequency&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ultra High Frequency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Low frequency&lt;/strong&gt;:
It is generally called swing trading. You can consider any strategy that doesn’t operate intraday as Low Frequency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High Frequency&lt;/strong&gt;:
All intraday strategies are High Frequency strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ultra-High Frequency&lt;/strong&gt;:
Strategies which holds trades for seconds to milliseconds come under this classification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going from zero to live deployment in trading consists of six steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Strategy Identification&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Strategy Backtesting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Building an Execution System&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;System Risk Management&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Live Testing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Live Trading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the further posts of this series, we will look at these six steps in detail.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Introduction to Systematic Trading Systematic Trading is trading with well defined rules without any space for discretion. The two broad types of strategies relevant to retail traders are Trend-Following Mean-Reversion</summary></entry></feed>